Guide to the Poly Archives Memorabilia Collection RG.027
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Poly Archives Memorabilia Collection
1914-2019
1985-2014
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Polytechnic Institute of New York University
RG.027
25 Linear Feet in 25 boxes
Biographical / Historical
Brooklyn Collegiate & Polytechnic Institute (BCPI) was founded in 1854 as a school for young men. In 1889 it separated into a school for boys, Poly Prep, and the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (PIB). It was also known as the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute (BPI) and, affectionately, as "Brooklyn Poly." In 1973, the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn merged with the former New York University Heights engineering campus (acquiring students and staff) and became the Polytechnic Institute of New York (PINY). It again changed its name in 1985 to the Polytechnic University, which it remained until the 2008 affiliation with New York University, which created the Polytechnic Institute of NYU, also known as NYU-Poly. In 2014, Poly officially merged with NYU and became the NYU Polytechnic School of Engineering - renamed a year later the Tandon School of Engineering.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials produced by Polytechnic or related institutions and groups including documents, banners, regalia, t-shirts, and other realia. The items cover the eras from the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn to the NYU Polytechnic School of Engineering. Both the groups of t-shirts and realia contain no materials from the Polytechnic Institute of New York era.
Arrangement
The collection was arranged by the Archives and is divided by primary material type into five series: Documents, Banners, Academic Regalia, T-Shirts, and Realia. The Banners series is divided into four sub-types: General University, Commencement, Alumni, and Class Pennants. The T-Shirts and Realia series are both divided by university era into: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, Polytechnic University, Polytechnic Institute of New York University, NYU Polytechnic School of Engineering, and Miscellaneous.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open for research without restriction.
Custodial History
This collection was constructed from multiple historical accessions in the Archives as well as materials which were found undescribed on various shelves or boxes within the Archives. However, many items with known provenance came from alumni donors, the Poly alumni relations office, and facilities.
Memorabilia; T-shirts; Regalia; Banners; Pennants; Paperweights; Decorative plates
- Series I: Documents
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains both documentary memorabilia and documentation about other items in the collection (Realia Series).
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Files with names in the title have been donated by or on behalf of those Polytechnic alumni.
  - Library Display Layouts, 2014, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alan Postman - Dance Card, Invitation, Menu, 1914-1917, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Course Cards (Polytechnic Institute of New York), circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Leonard Mangiaracina Acceptance and Enrollment Documents, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Schatzman Ring Provenance, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Albert Newman Memorabilia, 1918-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Milton Bassin (Alumnus) Photo and Card, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Poly Tau Epsilon Phi Memorabilia and Poly Reporters (Gabe Goldberg '58), 1966-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - One Hundred and Eighteenth Annual Commencement Booklet, 1973-05-31 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II: Polytechnic Banners
  Many of the General University banners and the Commencement banners were acquired from the facilities department. The Class Pennants were found in two boxes in the Archives, undescribed, but may have originally come from the student lounge.
  - Subseries A: General University Banners
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York Pennant, 12" x 29", undated (Box 2, Object 1)
    - Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute (BPI) Banner, undated (Box 2, Object 2)
    - Polytechnic University, "Celebrating 150 Years in Brooklyn" Banner, undated (Box 2, Object 3)
    - Polytechnic University Banner, undated (Box 2, Object 4)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York University pennant, purple, undated (Box 2, Object 8)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York Pennant, 11.5' x 3', undated (Box 3, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University, "Celebrating 150 Years in Brooklyn" Banner, undated (Box 3, Object 2)
    - "Polytechnic University: Tomorrow's Technology Today" Banner, undated (Box 4, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University Banner with yellow fringe, undated (Box 5, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University Banner with seal, undated (Box 5, Object 2)
    - Polytechnic University pennant, blue, undated (Map-case 3)
    - NYU-Poly banner, purple, undated (Box 25, Object 1)
  - Subseries B: Commencement Banners
    - Civil Engineering commencement banners, 31" x 25" chevrons, 2013 (Box 6, Object 1-2)
    - Civil Engineering commencement banners, 78" x 5", 2013 (Box 6, Object 3-4)
    - Chemical and Biological Sciences commencement banners, 31" x 25" chevrons, 2013 (Box 6, Object 5-6)
    - Chemical and Biological Sciences commencement banners, 78" x 5", 2013 (Box 6, Object 7-8)
    - Chemical and Biological Engineering commencement banners, 31" x 25" chevrons, 2013 (Box 6, Object 9-10)
    - Chemical and Biological Engineering commencement banners, 78" x 5", 2013 (Box 6, Object 11-12)
    - Polytechnic School of Engineering commencement banner, 2014 (Box 7, Object 1)
  - Subseries C: Alumni Banners
    - Polytechnic Alumni, Philadelphia Chapter Banner, undated (Box 2, Object 5)
    - Polytechnic Alumni, Big Apple Chapter, undated (Box 2, Object 6)
    - Polytechnic Alumni, Houston Chapter Banner, undated (Box 2, Object 7)
  - Subseries D: Class Pennants
    General
    The class pennants originally hung in the student lounge at [??] and are each 46" x 18".
    - Poly Class Pennants: 1855-1907, 1855, 1875, 1888, 1890, 1891, 1893-1898, 1900-1907 (Box 8, Object 1-19)
    - Poly Class Pennants: 1908-1936, 1908, 1909 (x2), 1910-1916, 1927-1933, 1935, 1936 (Box 9, Object 1-19)
    - Poly Class Pennants: 1912, 1917-1927 (Box 10, Object 1-12)
    - Poly Class Pennants: 1938-1974, 1938, 1940, 1942, 1946, 1947, 1949-1953, 1956, 1957, 1960, 1962, 1963, 1965, 1966, 1968-1970, 1974 (Box 11, Object 1-21)
- Series III: Academic Regalia
  The Board of Trustee commencement set came to the Archives as a transfer from the Dean's office, while the other robe and hood were found in President Jerry Hultin's office suite.
  - Commencement hood, green and orange, undated (Box 12, Object 1)
  - Commencement robe, black, undated (Box 12, Object 2)
  - Polytechnic Board of Trustees commencement cap, undated (Box 13, Object 1)
  - Polytechnic Board of Trustees commencement hood, undated (Box 13, Object 2)
  - Polytechnic Board of Trustees commencement robe, undated (Box 13, Object 3)
- Series IV: T-Shirts
  - Subseries A: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn T-Shirts
    - Brooklyn Poly Phys. Ed. t-shirt, white, undated (Box 14, Object 14)
  - Subseries B: Polytechnic University T-Shirts
    - Polytechnic University t-shirt, gray, undated (Box 14, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University long-sleeved t-shirt, gray, undated (Box 14, Object 2)
    - Orientation leader t-shirt, blue, undated (Box 14, Object 6)
    - NSCE 2007 t-shirt, red (Box 14, Object 14)
    - Polytechnic University t-shirt, black, undated (Box 14, Object 15)
    - HEOP Works t-shirt, white, undated (Box 14, Object 16)
    - Poly Pride - i2e Embracing Diversity t-shirt, black, undated (Box 15, Object 3)
    - Super Poly - Poly Pride Day t-shirt, blue, 2008 (Box 15, Object 7)
    - CSAW "Battles in the Cyber World" t-shirt, black, 2007 (Box 15, Object 10)
    - Polytechnic University polo, blue, undated (Box 15, Object 13)
    - Polytechnic University polo, black, undated (Box 15, Object 14)
  - Subseries C: Polytechnic Institute of New York University T-Shirts
    - NYU-Poly i2e t-shirt, black, undated (Box 14, Object 3)
    - NYU-Poly t-shirt, red, undated (Box 14, Object 4)
    - NYU-Poly t-shirt, gray, undated (Box 14, Object 5)
    - Orientation leader t-shirt, yellow, undated (Box 14, Object 7)
    - PolyThinker - Poly Pride Day t-shirt, gray, 2010 (Box 14, Object 9-10)
    - New Student Camp Experience t-shirt, green, undated (Box 14, Object 11)
    - Class of 2014 #Engineering is... t-shirt, gray (Box 15, Object 4-5)
    - NYU-Poly t-shirt, purple, undated (Box 15, Object 6)
    - NYU-Poly - Poly Pride Day t-shirt, black, 2009 (Box 15, Object 8)
    - CSAW - Cyber Security Awareness Week t-shirt, yellow, 2008 (Box 15, Object 9)
    - "Hack Into Your True Potential" CSAW t-shirt, black, undated (Box 15, Object 11)
    - Midnight Madness t-shirt, white, October 24, 2008 (Box 15, Object 12)
    - Residence life polo, white, undated (Box 15, Object 15)
    - Peer counselor polo, purple, undated (Box 15, Object 16)
    - Peer counselor polo, yellow, undated (Box 15, Object 17)
    - Graduate School t-shirt, white, undated (Box 15, Object 18)
  - Subseries D: New York University - Polytechnic School of Engineering T-Shirts
    - Engineering is NYU t-shirt, white, undated (Box 15, Object 1)
    - Engineering is NYU t-shirt, black, undated (Box 15, Object 2)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous T-Shirts
    - NYU Athletics polo, blue, undated (Box 14, Object 8)
    - Programming Advisory Board Chocolate Week t-shirt, brown, undated (Box 14, Object 12)
    - U Know It All t-shirt, green, undated (Box 14, Object 13)
- Series V: Realia
  - Subseries A: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Realia
    - Polytechnic Tie, "Paul Cooper '58, Gift to Library", undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ticket to basketball game - Iona College vs. Brooklyn Poly, February 25, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Murad Cigarette College Series 26-50 card - PIB, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Murad Cigarette College Series 26-50 card - PIB, 2nd edition, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Jeff Schatzman AEP class ring, 1969 (Box 18, Object 6)
    - Brooklyn Poly 150 pin, undated (Box 19, Object 1)
    - PIB pins from William Aghassi '69, undated (Box 19, Object 9)
    - Polytechnic College of Engineering button, gray, undated (Box 20, Object 2)
    - Slide rule from Harold Krane, undated (Box 21, Object 11)
    - Slide rule in case, undated (Box 21, Object 12)
    - Post Universal Slide Rule, Model 1459, undated (Box 21, Object 13)
    - Post Universal Slide Rule, Model 1459 - documentation, 2013 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Slide Rule from Hermann Broeker, 1949 (Box 21, Object 53)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Ceramic Mug (Box 18, Item 7)
  - Subseries B: Polytechnic University Realia
    - Polytechnic scarf, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Polytechnic University metal bookmark, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Polytechnic University seal die, circa 1985 (Box 16, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University flashlight, white, undated (Box 17, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University flashlight, NSCE 2007 (Box 17, Object 2)
    - Polytechnic University mug, black, undated (Box 17, Object 3)
    - Polytechnic University mug with seal, undated (Box 17, Object 4)
    - Dibner Library mug, "Celebrating 10 years of innovative service", undated (Box 17, Object 5)
    - Polytechnic University pewter keychain, undated (Box 19, Object 6)
    - Poly Welcomes Maxwell button, blue, undated (Box 19, Object 7)
    - Polytechnic University - 1854 Society pin, undated (Box 19, Object 8)
    - Plastic paperweights containing tickets to "Polytechnic University 150th & Inauguration", September 29, 2005 (Box 21, Object 1-2)
    - Marble Polytechnic University paperweight, "In Appreciation", undated (Box 21, Object 3)
    - Marble paperweight, "The Campaign for Polytechnic: Fulfilling the American Dream, 1997-2001" (Box 21, Object 4)
    - Plastic paperweight, "The Campaign for Polytechnic: Fulfilling the American Dream, 1997-2001" (Box 21, Object 5)
    - Polytechnic University metal pencil holder, undated (Box 21, Object 6)
    - Polytechnic University tie, undated (Box 21, Object 8)
    - Small stuffed panda with "Polytechnic University" shirt, undated (Box 21, Object 9)
    - Small stuffed mouse with "Polytechnic University" shirt, undated (Box 21, Object 10)
    - Sesquicentennial PolyThinker medal (unengraved), circa 2004 (Box 21, Object 14)
    - 'Polytechnic at Metrotech' buttons, gray, undated (Box 21, Object 16-52)
    - Polytechnic Prom 1980 stemware (Box 21, Item 53-54)
    - Polytechnic Construction/[iversit] hard hat, white, undated (Box 22, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic University Freshman Orientation Week hard hat, yellow, 2000 (Box 22, Object 2)
    - Poly Paint-A-Thon fabric cap, white, 1996 (Box 22, Object 3)
    - i2e sculpture, undated (Box 22, Object 4)
    - Polytechnic cap, blue, undated (Box 22, Object 5)
    - Polytechnic scarf, undated (Box 24, Object 7)
  - Subseries C: Polytechnic Institute of New York University Realia
    - Polytechnic Institute of NYU seal die, undated (Box 16, Object 2)
    - Polytechnic Institute of NYU mug, undated (Box 18, Object 1)
    - Polytechnic Institute of NYU water bottle, undated (Box 18, Object 2)
    - Polytechnic Institute of NYU binders, undated (Box 18, Object 3-4)
    - Polytechnic Institute of NYU plastic mug, undated (Box 18, Object 5)
    - NYU-Poly Alumni pins, purple, undated (Box 19, Object 3-4)
    - Small glass globe, "NYU-Poly: Polytechnic Institute of New York University", undated (Box 21, Object 15)
    - Small glass globe, "NYU-Poly: Polytechnic Institute of New York University", undated (Box 24, Object 2)
    - NYU-Poly small wallet, black, undated (Box 24, Object 3)
    - NYU-Poly clutch wallet, black, undated (Box 24, Object 4)
    - Leather and metal NYU-Poly business card holder, green, undated (Box 24, Object 5)
    - NYU-Poly pen and metal pen case, undated (Box 24, Object 6)
  - Subseries D: New York University - Polytechnic School of Engineering Realia
    - Polytechnic School of Engineering Alumni pin, white, undated (Box 19, Object 2)
    - Polytechnic School of Engineering keychain, white, undated (Box 19, Object 5)
    - "Engineering is...Creative / Global / Mobile / Now / Life" tote bag, purple, undated (Box 24, Object 1)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous Realia
    - We heart Poly button, blue, undated (Box 20, Object 1)
    - James Madison High School Senior button, yellow, Jan. 1945 (Box 20, Object 3)
    - Albert Jay Newman U.S. Army button, blue, undated (Box 20, Object 4)
    - Plastic paperweight containing image of Brooklyn Collegiate & Polytechnic Institute building, undated (Box 21, Object 7)
    - Gablinger's Beer can, undated (Box 21, Object 55)
      Biographical / Historical
      Poly alumnus Joseph Owades (July 9, 1919 December 16, 2005) worked on the development of "light" beer. He worked for Fleischmann's Yeast, Schwarz Labs, and Rheingold Breweries in Brooklyn, where he became Vice PresidentTechnical Director. Rheingold introduced the first "light beer," Gablinger's, using an enzyme which broke down chains of starch, allowing yeast to digest all of the starch. This created a beer with lower calories. Polytechnic Alumni President Anthony Concolino used this can of Gablinger's beer in his 2019 convocation speech, demonstrating the inventive spirit of Poly/Tandon engineers. Concolino donated the beer can and two Polytechnic prom beer glasses to the Poly Archives in 2021.
      Owades source: Joseph Owades. (2023). Academic Dictionaries and Encyclopedias. Retrieved July 21, 2023, from https://en-academic.com/dic.nsf/enwiki/1665844
    - Poly commemorative plate with image of original BCPI building, circa 1970s (Box 23, Object 1-2)
    - Poly commemorative plate with image of 85 Livingston Street, circa 1970s (Box 23, Object 3-4)
    - Plate commemorating the dedication of the Othmer building, Washington D.C., January 22, 1990 (Box 23, Object 5)
    - Poly commemorative plate with image of Rogers Hall, closeup, circa 1970s (Box 23, Object 6-7)
    - Poly commemorative plate with image of Rogers Hall, wide view, circa 1970s (Box 23, Object 8)
- Series VI: 2019 Accretion, 1969-circa 1970s
  These items were donated to the Poly Archives by Curt and Linda Hoffman in the summer of 2019.
  Arrangement
  This donation is primarily housed in one box, with the exception of one item.
  These items include photographs, correspondence, stickers, and a pin. They are located in bay 39 shelf 7B.
  - Freshman Orientation Film 1969, undated (Box 26, Item 1)
  - Linda Hoffman Photographs, circa 1970s (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (PIB) Sticker, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Polytechnic Institute of New York Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - S.U.N.Y. Poly Pin, undated (Box 20, Item 5)
  - Polytechnic Letter from Office of the President to Polytechnic Applicants, 1969-04-11 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Series VII: 2025 Accretion
  - Gabriel Goldberg, Polytechnic Report Cards, 1964-1968 (Box 26, Folder 5)